<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ulyssis.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://ulyssis.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-10-12T22:00:39+00:00</updated><id>https://ulyssis.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Professional site of Siyu Tang
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">my data science application materials</title><link href="https://ulyssis.github.io/2021/10/11/jobapplications.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="my data science application materials" /><published>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ulyssis.github.io/2021/10/11/jobapplications</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ulyssis.github.io/2021/10/11/jobapplications.html">&lt;p&gt;After more than a decade of writing academic-style job applications, preparing materials for (first) data science job applications was a huge change. I wrote this post to share my approach and materials; I hope this will help other ex-academics (and perhaps other career-changers) reqrite their CVs and cover letters for a new challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am no expert! I have completed one data science job hunt, and I’ve only seen the other side of hiring once or twice in academia. If you are making your own career switch, please seek out supplemental advice, stories, and guides on your job quest. I always reccomend this list of resources from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.askamanager.org/2020/07/heres-a-bunch-of-help-finding-a-new-job.html&quot;&gt;Ask a Manager&lt;/a&gt;, I found it helped me both with practical application advice and with a perspective shift to what it’s like outside academia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-preparation-stage&quot;&gt;The preparation stage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started my hunt by reading every related job ad on LinkedIn and Indeed, without yet thinking about applying. I had very little idea what non-academic job ads were like when I started reading them. I knew I would be looking for data scientist jobs, but I ended up considering data analyst and data engineer roles as well. I started to get a sense of the range of jobs out there, the skills they were looking for, and where I wanted to focus on applying. I began my process by finding one job ad I was particularly excited about it, and writing my materials for that job specifically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I read more and more job ads, I also reached out to my social network. I told friends I was job hunting and I blasted it on twitter. That is not how I found my current job, but I got some connections, some example job application materials, offers to review my materials, and even a few non-advertised job opportunities. So many people came through with help, often where I least expected it. I think this is an essential step in putting together your job materials - activate your network, to the best of your ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;from-a-ten-page-cv-to-a-one-page-resume&quot;&gt;From a ten page CV to a one page resume&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When faced with this task, I began by looking for examples of data science resumes wherever I could find them (&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/pdf/sjs_cv_datascience_2021.pdf&quot;&gt;mine is here&lt;/a&gt;). I googled lots of advice about resumes in general and data science ones specifically and got plenty of it, both good and bad. After all that research, I found a google docs template and started filling it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I divided my resume into three main sections: education, experience, and skills. Here’s how I filled out each:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education:&lt;/strong&gt; Degrees and schools, with an additional section for workshops and online courses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experience:&lt;/strong&gt; A listing of my jobs, including “graduate assistant,” since a PhD is usually both education and work experience. To fill in descriptions, I picked 2-3 major projects I worked on at each institute, and wrote a single sentence for each, mentioning both how it used data and what it achieved. I gently revised these sentences over my months of applying to be more concise and contain less jargon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skills:&lt;/strong&gt; I approached this from two angles:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical:&lt;/strong&gt; This was very focused on what I know how to do. Python (with a package list) and SQL felt essential to include, even though I was self-conscious about my skill level (in retrospect: my skills were fine). I also listed things like data cleaning and visualization, chi-squared fitting, dimensionality reduction, etc. I got some strong recommendations to be explicit about how proficient I was in each skill, and so I added that as well.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication and Leadership:&lt;/strong&gt; For the rest of the skills section, I printed out my academic resume and grouped sections together and tried to sum up what they represent. For example, a half-page list of the students I mentored became “Supervised ten students through data-focused research projects.” My list of talks, including seminars, conference talks, and a few public talks became “Delivered over 30 seminars to both specialist and general audiences.”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, I sent my resume to others for feedback and incorporated it. I had two ex-astronomers working in data that had super useful comments, but a few more friends inside and outside tech helped me with style, phrasing, jargon reduction, and support. The audience for a CV isn’t only people on your team or in similar roles, but also people working in HR or on a broader engineering/tech team or leadership at the company. In that sense, feedback from insiders &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; outsiders is very important. I didn’t turn down anyone who offered to look at my resume, and got something out of it each time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a bit sad that not everyone has the time and energy to read the whole CV, even if it is (comparatively) short. Some scan for key words (usually ones that match the job ad), and some are only looking for very specific experience. I put my coding and work experience very clearly near the top for those folks. The people who noticed the details on the bottom of my CV (and asked me about them) were the team leads who were most genuinely interested in hiring me (including my current manager). To me, this indicated they respected breadth and depth of my experiences, and the rest of the process was figuring out if I was the right match for the role they were trying to fill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-field-new-cover-letter&quot;&gt;New field, new cover letter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cover letters are hard, and sometimes they seem like a thankless task. Some applications only ask for resumes, and others leave cover letters as optional. In my experience, companies that accept/request cover letters are more likely to be considering applicants that may have a broader range of experience. If you’re breaking into a new field, a cover letter is an important piece of your application and provides information on how your previous experiences have prepared you for this role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below, I’m sharing most of a real cover letter I submitted, with some context on how I put it together. There was an opening “I’m applying for…” sentence and a closing “Thank you for considering…” sentence, and between them I wrote three paragraphs: the first on my background, the second providing an example of my work, and the third describing my match with the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-general-background&quot;&gt;My general background&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first paragraph described my broad experience as an academic in terms of the general tasks that seemed to overlap with the new position. I focused on the work I did with large datasets and mentioned some techniques that I was used to using. My coding skills were not my main selling point, so I focused on data skills and being able to organize and execute projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I received my PhD in Astronomy in 2012, and have an additional eight years of experience in academic research using data-driven techniques. My scientific projects typically involved extracting and cross-matching data from multiple databases, analyzing, modeling, and visualizing it with IDL and Python, and communicating my findings to a broad range of audiences. Through these academic experiences, I’ve gained hands-on experience independently designing, executing, and completing large, hypothesis-testing projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my biggest surprises in my early interviews was when an interviewer expressed that they didn’t believe I’d be able to work independently on her team. I was shocked; I think of people with PhDs as having proved their ability to finish independent projects. This prompted me to think more deeply about what I view as my specific PhD-related skills, and make sure I mention them in my letter. For me, this was mostly independence, project management, quick learning, problem-solving, and communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-specific-example&quot;&gt;A specific example&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next paragraph, I picked the project that I thought was most like the work I’d do at the company and described it in more detail. I had about three versions of this paragraph, depending on what the job description was. This was my typical example, since it focuses on working with a large-ish dataset and my ability to be detail oriented and clean data. I also had examples that discussed my creative problem-solving and my experiences using data to improve the world around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As an astronomer, I developed a knack for working with large datasets. One of my main projects was focused on selecting and classifying 12,000 stars using data from five different sources, including multi-dimensional spectroscopic files. A major challenge was that the data did not meet a consistent set of quality checks across the entire sample. I focused on the details of the data, designing a series of tests and filters to ensure that each measurement was sufficient for the scientific questions it was being used to answer. This led to the novel discovery that strong magnetic fields are common on the smallest stars, and I gained a wealth of knowledge about the data and its uses that I was able to share with the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will say that reading it now, I’d tone down the jargon even more; for me, de-jargoning is like gradually peeling away the layers of an onion starting with the most blatant and moving towards the slightly opaque. But I think it served the purpose of showing I had some applicable skills and could use them to complete projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;my-fit-to-this-job&quot;&gt;My fit to this job&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third paragraph was the space where I would explain that I’m switching careers and address my specific fit within the company. It was useful here to read the job ad in detail and peruse the company website, especially the “work with us” or “about us” section. There were some really exciting and different positions where I would write this entire paragraph fresh, but there were also some combinations of company website and job ad that I felt I saw again and again. I’m sure there were real differences between them after meeting the people and getting to the actual work, but it was hard to see from the outside. Here is the example of a pretty generic one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;After spending fifteen years using data in an academic setting, I am ready for my work to have a more direct impact on the people around me. My background gives me an edge with scientific problem solving and communicating complex ideas to a variety of audiences, skills that I can bring to Company X to create data-driven solutions. I am new to a business environment, but I am a fast and eager learner and ready to take on a new challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Company X didn’t have much about their company culture, and I didn’t have some specific desire to work in Company X’s industry. Usually I can talk about shared values (for me, these are: feedback culture, teamwork, employee education), and for a few jobs I could get excited about their goals or industry (education, music, women-focused, eco/green). But this minimal example acknowledges that I have a different background than their usual candidate might, but why I am interested in the role anyhow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-thats-all-for-now&quot;&gt;And that’s all for now&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedback? Questions? My contact info is in the little icons below!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">After more than a decade of writing academic-style job applications, preparing materials for (first) data science job applications was a huge change. I wrote this post to share my approach and materials; I hope this will help other ex-academics (and perhaps other career-changers) reqrite their CVs and cover letters for a new challenge.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">from astronomy to data science</title><link href="https://ulyssis.github.io/2021/10/07/astro2data.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="from astronomy to data science" /><published>2021-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ulyssis.github.io/2021/10/07/astro2data</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ulyssis.github.io/2021/10/07/astro2data.html">&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk recently, during the 2021 meeting of the German Astronomical Society in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ag2021.astronomische-gesellschaft.de/view_splinter.php?session=Careers&quot;&gt;“Healthy Careers in Astronomy (and Beyond)”&lt;/a&gt; session. I called my talk &lt;a href=&quot;https://ag2021.astronomische-gesellschaft.de/view_abstract.php?id=157&quot;&gt;“From the stars back down to Earth: getting a job as a data scientist”&lt;/a&gt;” and attempted to give a fifteen minute overview of the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like the slides, &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/pdf/sjs_astro_to_datascience2021.pdf&quot;&gt;here they are&lt;/a&gt;! If you want similar information in blog form, read on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the talk quite difficult to put together for a few reasons. First off, I’m completely new to the online talk format. When many academics were moving from live to online talks at the pandemic onset, I was putting was my head down and trying to finish a few projects before leaving the field. Second, it’s deeply personal. My choices around my career path are rooted in my identities and inner landscape and speaking on those is not easy. Third, it’s a broad topic and I knew my audience would have a variety of perspectives and needs! Some may be entering the job market right now, others might be mentoring students knowing they may look for different jobs, and others still would be like I was - hoping I’d be an astronomy but wanting to be ready with plan B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it’s a broad topic, I did want to write a bit here about the various facets of my job search. Maybe I’ll start blogging devotedly and write more about each, maybe not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-i-made-the-move&quot;&gt;Why I made the move&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, I didn’t manage to get a permanent job. But there’s a bit more to it than that. Near the end of my last contract, I felt my mental health was being eroded by the structures of academia. I was constantly tense that I wasn’t producing enough, and that stress actually prevented me from effectively finishing projects. I was also feeling less and less like I belonged in academia, and less and less like I could change it for the better (either for me or others). I was not maintaining enough productivity or applying to enough professor positions to give myself a solid shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am pretty glad I’m out of academia. The work is not as cool (sorry current employer) but I can genuinely put it aside at the end of the day. I still get satisfaction from digging into data, solving problems, and learning new skills. I also am really glad that if I want to switch employers, I don’t have to move cities and leave my local community behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;working-in-germany-as-a-us-citezen&quot;&gt;Working in Germany as a US Citezen&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m from the Chicago suburbs and have strong ties to Seattle and NYC, but I chose to stay in Berlin after the end of my contract in Potsdam. I have a community here in Berlin, and work-wise I benefit from Germany-wide mandated 26 vacation days, sensible sick leave policies, and permanent contracts after six month probationary periods. There’s also unemployment money available for longer than in the US, giving people a better chance to find jobs. I also have felt that Germany’s handling of the pandemic lines up more closely with actual research (though could be improved).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But between unemployment, a job shift, and pandemic delays in bureaucracy, my visa status has been shaky all year. It is not great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-i-got-my-job&quot;&gt;How I got my job&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d heard this myth that many companies are snatching up ex-academics as data scientists and it’s super easy to stumble on a job. That was not my experience. I think that view is outdated (data engineers are now on-trend, and there’s still a pandemic), and may also be linked to seniority (easier to find a job fresh off a PhD), identity (white cis het dudes tend to have it easier), and geography (Berlin has a lot of job-seekers). I still feel it is very much possible, but it took a lot of time, effort, and energy for me to find my current position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over about 3-4 months, I submitted 101 applications for data analyst, scientist, and engineer roles at various levels of seniority. I heard back from 18, and for those companies I did 26 interviews and 8 tech tests. As I received feedback from early interviews and applications, I was able to iteratively improve my materials and be more prepared for interviews. Eventually I received two offers (actually within an hour of each other), one for a data analyst position at 48k, and one for a data scientist position at 60k.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most helpful online resources for me were Ask A Manager’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.askamanager.org/2020/07/heres-a-bunch-of-help-finding-a-new-job.html&quot;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt; and the data science track at &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.dataquest.io/&quot;&gt;dataquest&lt;/a&gt;. I got a bunch of advice, feedback, and a few job leads from asking my friends and twitter followers. The actual job I got was posted on linkedIn, but my network was ESSENTIAL for the feedback and support that I needed to improve my materials and interview skills, and to keep applying!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shifting-identities&quot;&gt;Shifting identities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the years that I was working as an astronomer, that was my primary identity. I think the culture of academia encourages that identification and I no longer found it to be heathy for me. In part because I now work in a different role, but also because I am less willing to allow wage labor to be the center of my identity. Changing identities is difficult though, and the work of trying to re-identify who I am is still ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mental-health&quot;&gt;Mental health&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had chronic depression, anxiety, and insomnia for a long time, and those conditions have been particularly difficult in the overlap between my career change and the global pandemic. I don’t have the energy today to go into detail, but want to be clear that mental health was both a motivator for my career change, and a factor that affected its path.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I gave a talk recently, during the 2021 meeting of the German Astronomical Society in the “Healthy Careers in Astronomy (and Beyond)” session. I called my talk “From the stars back down to Earth: getting a job as a data scientist”” and attempted to give a fifteen minute overview of the process.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">on failing</title><link href="https://ulyssis.github.io/2020/05/05/failure.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="on failing" /><published>2020-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ulyssis.github.io/2020/05/05/failure</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ulyssis.github.io/2020/05/05/failure.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ll start dramatically: I feel I’ve failed at academia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, logically, I know I haven’t. I have always rejected the notion that the only path to success is a tenured professor position. I’ve been supportive of friends leaving academia, and continue to be so pleased for those who have found other jobs, communities, causes, and lives. In my mentorship, my goal is to emphasize building a broad array of skills that can be used not just in other jobs, but also in other areas of life. And I’m well aware that there simply aren’t enough jobs for all the excellent candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that logic really has not fixed the feelings of failure and rejection that have been lingering in the back of my mind while I’ve been focused on other things (mostly the pandemic). So I’ve been thinking it through again, by allowing myself to accept the premise that I’ve failed and see where that takes me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failure, to me, implies the absence of reaching a specific goal. I committed myself to the academic career path over fifteen years ago, and it’s amazing how strongly I’ve clung to the idea of myself as a professor. I adopted ‘academic’ and ‘astronomer’ as my identities, and allowed them to shape and reshape my self-conception. For a while, I was really well-suited to my PhD and post-doc positions, and believed that I’d make an excellent professor. I was optimistic about my chances to stay in my field, and to change it for the better. I had a very specific vision of what my future would look like at some anonymous university where I’d fit in perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this year’s job rejections shattered that vision. I had failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And first, I countered those feelings of failure with logic. I know that due to my training and my privilege, I am unlikely to be unemployed for long. I can also point to many ways that I don’t actually think I’d be very happy continuing in traditional academia. I can think about the sheer numbers of qualified and excellent candidates applying for each professorship. I can even recognize that if staying in academia was my specific goal, there are still pathways, so I haven’t actually failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But still, I’ve given up. I’m done. I have always believed that I could do anything I put my mind to. Positive words, but with their own downside. If I’m capable of anything, I must have had some particular failing - made poor choices or perhaps too many mistakes. At first, I simply beat myself up about that, but more recently I dug into the reasons I made those choices and mistakes. And it really boils down to the fact that astronomy, at least within traditional academia, is just not for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ‘not for me’ thing is not a concept I’m very familiar with. I value a broad range of experiences, and I find myself interested in just about everything. This results in an ever changing and growing list of hobbies, music genres, books to read, and now, jobs to explore. In other words, I often think there’s almost nothing that is ‘not for me.’ I can, after all, do anything I put my mind to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s just not true. Of course my interests aren’t infinite, and even among the bunches of things I like and enjoy, there are some that I’d rather not do all the time. Some things are difficult, stressful, or simply less fulfilling. Over the past few years, I think astronomy slipped from one of my favorite things to something that I’d rather not do all the time. It shifted gradually, quietly, and during a time when I was going through a lot of chaos in other areas of my life. But I’ve changed, and it’s not for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said before, I’ve put fifteen years of time and energy into academia, so it’s been difficult to admit that much of the joy was gone. I’ve struggled a bit with my productivity, but kept holding out for a recovery, a return to my old interests. A resounding NO from the job market really has helped me realize that it’s not just a phase. Perhaps I’ve failed at academia, but the part of the failure that’s on me is really a reflection of my waning interest in it, and my lack of compatibility with the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And am I just rejecting academia because it rejected me? MAYBE. I can’t promise that I would have turned down a tenure-track job, or been unhappy in one. But I would have had to change from who I am now, and to grow in a different direction to make it work. Better to be excited about growing apart from academia, than to get too caught up in the failure and what might have been.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’ll start dramatically: I feel I’ve failed at academia.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">leaving academia</title><link href="https://ulyssis.github.io/2020/02/27/end.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="leaving academia" /><published>2020-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://ulyssis.github.io/2020/02/27/end</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ulyssis.github.io/2020/02/27/end.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been through a couple serious breakups in the past few years, and I remember there was a period of time before the actual break where I knew I was unhappy, but was trying to figure out if there was a way to fix it. Then there was this moment of clarity where I realized that I’d been denying that a good thing had come to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year’s rejections worked like that. I’m nearly eight years post-phd, and very familiar with that feeling of checking the rumor mill and finding myself unsucessful in getting a faculty slot. This time, my postdoc contract also ends in the fall, leaving me in academic limbo. There are worse things, and many a scientist in this situation has gotten some grant or moved for a third postdoc and eventually found the right position. But I am unwilling to fight to stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Astronomy used to excite me. Not just at specific moments, but overall. I felt a fascination and absorption in the great task of figuring out what is going on in our universe. I relished the whole process of research and kept getting carried away by some new idea that I didn’t mean to spend the afternoon exploring. I loved the process of writing, looked forward to giving talks, and felt so at home in the research community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because one highlight has been the people I’ve met. Such strong, fascinating, brilliant people in our field. When I went to my first conferences 14 years ago, I had no idea how many friends and collaborators and role models I could find within astronomy. And the marvelous things you all would be accomplishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s been a dark side too. I used too much alcohol to cope while in grad school. In the last months of my PhD, I acquired a chronic back injury due to stress and anxiety; it flares up when my mental or physical self care wanes. At times I have felt very isolated, demoralized, and marginalized. I’ve witnessed more sexism, racism, and ablism than I would have imagined and some of it from people who have disappointed me greatly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently making my best efforts to deal with depression, anxiety, and insomnia. None of these were created by academia, but they weren’t improved by it. My approach to treatment has included some medication, but more important are using therapy to learn to deal with my feelings and re-structuring my life for better mental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the structural changes that are right for me, I’m tuning in to what makes me happy and excited, when I feel productive and strong. That used to be my work, but lately I’ve been carried away with my balcony garden, with re-organizing my appartment, with learning to bake really good bread. Intellectually, I’m most fascinaed by the links between capitalism, the patriarchy, and mental health and trying to learn more about both difference feminism and intersectionality. In my non-work time, I’ve been working with a group of women to understand methods for collective non-heirarchical leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’m burned out. I’ve found academia generally to be a high pressure, low support (not zero support, but not structurally supportive) environment. I’ve done my best to make it less so for myself, my collaborators, and my students, but I think it’s a structural inevitability and I’m exhausted by it. I’m not sure what’s coming after my end of contract in September (beyond staying in Berlin, learning more German, and taking some time to think) but I know a little bit more about what I don’t want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to do my best to document my next moves a bit, through some combo of twitter and this blog. Stay tuned for more soul searching, job searching, and probably some anti-capitalist rants.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been through a couple serious breakups in the past few years, and I remember there was a period of time before the actual break where I knew I was unhappy, but was trying to figure out if there was a way to fix it. Then there was this moment of clarity where I realized that I’d been denying that a good thing had come to an end.</summary></entry></feed>